Welcome back!
欢迎回来!
In the previous step, we solved the problem for printing even numbers in a Functional approach.
在上一步骤中，我们用函数式方法解决了打印偶数的问题。
However, we needed to create a separate method, isEven.
然而，我们需要创建一个单独的方法，isEven。
We saw that the logic for this method is very very simple, and we had to do a lot of ceremony.
我们看到这个方法的逻辑非常非常简单，而我们不得不做很多仪式。
We had to add in a lot of detail to define the method and call it from here.
我们不得不加入很多细节来定义这个方法并从这里调用它。
Is there a simpler way of doing it?
有没有一个更简单的方法呢？
Let's look at it right now.
让我们现在就来看看。
The simpler way of defining this specific thing is called a Lambda Expression.
定义这个特定事物的更简单的方法叫做Lambda表达式。
So, what I'll do is, I'll comment this and I'll say .filter and over here,
所以，我将做的是，我将注释这个，我将说.filter和over here、
what do we want to do is, we would want to define a Lambda Expression. So, what is a Lambda Expression?
我们要做的是，我们要定义一个Lambda表达式。那么，什么是Lambda表达式？
A Lambda Expression is nothing but a simpler way of defining another method.
兰姆达表达式只不过是定义另一个方法的一种更简单的方式。
So, Lambda Expression is nothing but a method.
所以，Lambda Expression只不过是一个方法。
Very very simple.
非常非常简单。
However, in the Lambda Expression, you'd use a simpler syntax for creating this method.
然而，在Lambda Expression中，你会使用一种更简单的语法来创建这个方法。
What does this method accept as a parameter?
这个方法接受什么作为参数？
Let's start with that.
让我们从这个开始。
So, this method accepts number as the parameter, right?
那么，这个方法接受数字作为参数，对吗？
So, what do we want to do is, we'd want to take number as the parameter and we would want to check.
那么，我们要做的是，我们要把数字作为参数，然后我们要检查。
What do we want to check?
我们要检查什么？
We'd want to check, if number mod 2 == 0.
我们想检查，如果number mod 2 == 0。
So, we would want to take a number and we would want to check, if
所以，我们要取一个数字，然后检查，如果
number mod 2 == 0, and return it back.
number mod 2 == 0，并将其返回。
And this is something of a special kind of a syntax related to Lambda Expression.
这是与Lambda Expression有关的一种特殊语法。
It's hyphen, followed by greater than symbol.
它是连字符，后面是大于符号。
So, this is almost like an arrow symbol.
所以，这几乎就是一个箭头符号。
So, what we are saying in here is, take the number in. So, take the number and check if number mod 2 == 0
所以，我们在这里说的是，把这个数字拿进去。所以，取数字并检查数字的模数2是否==0
and return it back. By default, in Lambda Expressions, if you just have
并将其返回。默认情况下，在Lambda表达式中，如果你只是有
one statement present, it will return that value back.
一条语句，它就会返回这个值。
So, what would happen in here?
那么，在这里会发生什么？
It takes the number and returns the value of  number mod 2 == 0.
它接收数字并返回number mod 2 == 0的值。
How do I use it in our code?
我如何在我们的代码中使用它？
I just need to copy this and put it in between parenthesis of filter.
我只需要复制这个，把它放在过滤器的括号之间。
So, what we are defending in here is, saying number, for each number,
所以，我们在这里所做的辩护是，说数字，对于每个数字、
for each number, what do we want to do? Check, if number mod 2 == 0.
对于每个数字，我们要做什么？检查，如果number mod 2 == 0。
If number mod 2 == 0, then return True back.
如果number mod 2 == 0，那么返回True。
Otherwise, return False back.
否则，返回False。
Let's see what would happen. Cool!
让我们看看会发生什么。很好!
No change in output, but you can see that now the code is much much more simpler,
输出没有变化，但是你可以看到，现在的代码要简单得多、
because I don't really need to worry about this method anymore.
因为我真的不需要再担心这个方法了。
So, this method can be commented out and all logic that we have right now;
所以，这个方法可以被注释掉，而我们现在拥有的所有逻辑；
I'll move this line of code a little below.
我将把这行代码移到下面一点。
So, the logic that we have right now is to convert the list of numbers into a stream
所以，我们现在的逻辑是将数字列表转换成一个流
and for each of the numbers execute the filter.
并对每个数字执行过滤器。
So, is this condition True?
那么，这个条件是真的吗？
If the condition is True, then go ahead and do the print. As you can see in here, with functional programming,
如果条件是 "真"，那么就继续做打印。正如你在这里看到的，用函数式编程、
we are focusing on the, 'What to do?'.
我们专注于 "做什么"。
For each element, what to check? You are checking that the number is even.
对于每个元素，要检查什么？你正在检查这个数字是否是偶数。
For each element, what to do if the condition is True.
对于每个元素，如果条件为真，该怎么做？
We would want to print it out. The thing which we learned in this specific step is something called a
我们想把它打印出来。在这个具体步骤中，我们学到的东西叫做
Lambda Expression.
兰姆达表达式。
So, Lambda Expression, as we discussed, is a simplified representation of the method.
所以，Lambda表达式，正如我们所讨论的，是方法的简化表示。
So over here, we had a method called isEven,
所以在这里，我们有一个叫做isEven的方法、
which was returning number mod 2 == 0.
它的返回结果是数字mod 2 == 0。
We just used the same logic in here, in much more simpler syntax.
我们只是在这里用同样的逻辑，用更简单的语法。
If this is the first Lambda Expression that you wrote, the syntax might look a little weird, little new,
如果这是你写的第一个Lambda Expression，那么这个语法可能看起来有点奇怪，有点新鲜、
and all that. Don't worry, we will be writing a number of Lambda Expressions in the
和所有这些。别担心，我们将在随后的步骤中编写大量的Lambda表达式。
subsequent steps and you'd really get comfortable with them.
我们将在随后的步骤中编写大量的Lambda表达式，你会真正适应它们的。
Let's quickly review the important concepts that we have learned until now.
让我们快速回顾一下到目前为止我们所学到的重要概念。
Number one, with functional programming,
第一，对于函数式编程，我们关注的是做什么、
we focus on what to do.
我们专注于做什么。
We convert the numbers into a stream and for each element in that stream,
我们将数字转换成一个流，对于该流中的每个元素、
we specify what needs to be done.
我们指定需要做什么。
A stream is nothing but a sequence of elements.
一个流只不过是一个元素的序列。
For each element, we would want to call the isEven method in here
对于每个元素，我们想在这里调用isEven方法
and we use a method reference to define that in here.
我们在这里使用一个方法引用来定义它。
The other approach to defining what needs to be done
另一种方法是定义需要对每个数字做什么
with each number, is something called a Lambda Expression. With a Lambda Expression,
的另一种方法是用一个叫做Lambda Expression的东西来定义需要对每个数字做什么。使用Lambda表达式、
you can define the entire code directly in here. With a method reference,
你可以直接在这里定义整个代码。用一个方法引用、
we are actually referring to a method which is defined somewhere else.
我们实际上是在引用一个在其他地方定义的方法。
However, with the Lambda Expression, we are actually defining the complete logic of the method right here.
然而，通过Lambda表达式，我们实际上是在这里定义了方法的完整逻辑。
I hope you are having a lot of fun and I'm sure a lot of these concepts are new
我希望你玩得很开心，我相信这些概念有很多都是新的。
and as I said earlier, FP, functional programming, is actually a paradigm shift.
正如我之前所说，FP，函数式编程，实际上是一种范式的转变。
So, it will take some time for you to get adjusted to this.
所以，你需要一些时间来适应这个。
So, follow along and keep watching the next steps
所以，请跟随并继续关注接下来的步骤
and I'm sure you'll be learning a lot about functional programming.
我相信你会学到很多关于函数式编程的知识。
I'll see you in the next step.
我们下一步见。
Until then bye-bye.
在那之前，拜拜。